A Guide to the Dabney-Jackson Collection, 1716, 1744-1867
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Dabney-Jackson Collection, 1716, 1744-1867
Library of Virginia
24816
.675 cubic feet
Charles William Dabney
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by Charles William Dabney, ca. 1928-1929.
Biographical Information
Thomas Jonathan "Stonewall" Jackson was born 21 January 1824 in Clarksburg, Virginia, to Jonathan Jackson (1790-1826) and Julia Beckwith Neale Jackson (1798-1831). He attended West Point and became an instructor at Virginia Military Institute in Lexington, Virginia. Jackson married first Elinor Junkin (1825-1854) on 4 August 1853. After her death during childbirth, Jackson married Mary Anna Morrison (1831-1915) of North Carolina on 16 July 1857. They had two daughters, Mary Graham Jackson (b. 1858) and Julia Laura Jackson (1862-1889). After Jackson's death 10 May 1863, Mary Anna Jackson returned to North Carolina. She became known as the "Widow of the Confederacy" and became the honorary president of the United Daughters of the Confederacy. She wrote about her husband and traveled about speaking on him. Mary Anna Jackson died 24 March 1915 in Charlotte, North Carolina.
Robert Lewis Dabney (1820-1898), Presbyterian clergyman and teacher, was an educator associated with Hampden-Sydney College and with the Union Seminary of Virginia at Farmville, Virginia, 1836-1837, 1844, and 1853-1883. He married Lavinia Morrison (1828-1908) in 1855, and together they had several children including Charles William Dabney (1855-1945). During the Civil War he served with the Confederate Army of Northern Virginia, first as a chaplain with the 18th Virginia Infantry Regiment in 1861, then as an officer and chief of staff for Stonewall Jackson in 1862. After Jackson's death in 1863, Dabney wrote a biography of the general entitled Life and Campaigns of Lieutenant-General Thomas J. Jackson (1866). He was the son of Charles William Dabney (1786-1833) and Elizabeth Price Dabney, and the brother of Charles William Dabney (1809-1895), who served during the Civil War, in 1861 and 1862, as the captain of Company C, 15th Virginia Infantry Regiment.
Charles William Dabney (1786-1833) was the son of Samuel Dabney (1752-1812) and Jane Meriwether Dabney. Samuel Dabney was the son of William Dabney (1718-1776) and Ann Barret Dabney. Charles Dabney (ca. 1744- 1829), a son of William Dabney, served as an officer during the American Revolution in the 2nd Virginia State Regiment.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the papers, 1716, 1744-1834, of the Dabney family of Hanover, King William, and Louisa Counties, Virginia, and the papers, 1815-1867 (bulk, 1847-1867), of Thomas Jonathan "Stonewall" Jackson (1824-1863). These papers were compiled by Charles William Dabney (1855-1945) from various sources including his father, R. L. Dabney (1820-1898), Stonewall Jackson's chief of staff who used the papers to write Life and Campaigns of Lieutenant-General Thomas J. Jackson (1866).
Arrangement
Arrangement
Chronologically with undated items at the end of the series.
Organization
Organized into the following two series: I. Dabney Family Papers, 1716, 1744-1834; II. T. J. "Stonewall" Jackson Papers, 1815-1867 (bulk, 1847-1867)
Contents List
- Dabney Family Papers, 1716, 1744-1834 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  Principally consists of letters written by, to, or concerning Dabney family members, the chief individuals being William Dabney (1718-1776), Revolutionary War officer Charles Dabney (ca. 1744-1829), his wife Elizabeth Dabney, George Dabney (1760-1843), Samuel Dabney (1752-1812), James Dabney, Charles William Dabney (1786-1833), and former Virginia Lieutenant Governor John Guerrant (1760-1813). Within this series there are also Dabney family accounts, affidavits, agreements, certificates, deeds, indentures, military reports, Revolutionary War military land warrants, plats, powers of attorney, receipts, and an oversize copy of the Articles of Capitulation signed at Yorktown on 19 October 1781.
  Arranged chronologically
  - Deed. George Alves of New Kent County, to George Dabney of King William County, 10 October 1716, 1; Unspecified acreage of land "upon the upper line of the said George Alves's tract in the fork between the South Branch of Pamunky River." No recordation shown. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accounts. Unidentified, 1744-1746, 1a; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Morgan Thomas and Company, Bristol, to William Dabney, merchant in Hanover County, York River, Virginia, 20 August 1754, 2; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter. William Winston [Jr.?], B. F., to [William Dabney?], n. p., 16 April 1756, 3; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Morgan Thomas and Company, Bristol, to William Dabney, n. p., 13 November 1756, 4; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Morgan Thomas and Company, Bristol, to William Dabney, n. p., 1757, 5; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter. P[atrick] Henry, Jr., n. p., to [William Dabney?], n. p., 14 October 1760, 6; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Ed. Ambler, James Town, to Col. William Dabney, in Hanover, 24 February 1765, 7; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Ed. Ambler, James Town, to Charles Dabney, in Hanover, 23 May 1768, 8; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter. Mary Ambler, James Town, to Col. William Dabney, in Hanover, 15 December 1768, 9; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter. William [Nelson?], York, to Col. William Dabney, in Hanover, 18 January 1769, 10; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter. John Blair, Jr., James Town, to [William Dabney?], n. p., 1 April 1769, 11; 3 pp.; With postscript of Mary Ambler. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter. John Dabney, n. p., to [___], 29 April 1769, 12; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter. Mary Ambler, James Town, to Charles Dabney, in Hanover, 20 December 1769, 13; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter. [William Morris?], n. p., to Charles Dabney, n. p., 3 March 177-, 14; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificate of James Dabney concerning Joseph Street, of Louisa County, 17 June 1772, 15; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter. [Mary Ambler?], Williamsburg, to Charles Dabney, in Hanover, 13 March 1773, 16; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter. John Barret, n. p., to Charles Dabney, in Hanover, 25 August 1773, 17; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agreement. George, Susanna, Charles, Robert, and Samuel Dabney to divide their deceased father's slaves among them, 19 January 1774, 17a; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter. George Dabney, Hanover, to his brother Lieutenant Col. Charles Dabney of the 2nd Virginia Battalion, Head Quarters, n. p., 28 July 1778, 18; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter. George Dabney in Hanover County, Virginia, to his brother [Colonel Charles Dabney?], 24 October 1778, 18a; 2 pp.; Incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Morning reports of various companies of the 2nd Virginia State regiment, 1779, 19; 10 pp. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter. George Dabney in Hanover County, Virginia, to his brother [Colonel Charles Dabney?], 3 February 1779, 19a; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter. George Dabney in Hanover County, Virginia, to his brother [Colonel Charles Dabney?], 18 April 1779, 19b; 1 p.; Incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letter. Samuel Dabney, Cub Creek, Louisa [County], to his brother Lieutenant. Col. Charles Dabney of the 2nd Virginia State regiment, n. p., 21 April 1779, 20; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter. George Dabney, Hanover, to his brother [Charles Dabney], n. p., 3 July 1779, 21; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter. George Dabney in Hanover County, Virginia, to his brother Colonel Charles Dabney, 1 August 1779, 21a; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter. George Dabney, Hanover, to his brother [Charles Dabney], n. p., 6 September 1779, 22; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Articles of capitulation, [Yorktown], 19 October 1781, 23; 2 pp.; Apparently a negative photocopy of a manuscript borrowed from the Virginia Historical Society by Charles William Dabney.
  - "A Return of all the Men absent and present belonging to the Cavalry of Lieutenant Col. [Charles] Dabney's Legion," 26 April 1782, 24; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Revolutionary War bounty land military warrants, 1783-1786, 24a; 14 pp.; Principally concerning warrants issued to Colonel Charles Dabney. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter. John Lee in Kentucky to Colonel Charles Dabney in Hanover County, Virginia, 29 August 1794, 24b; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Deed. Robert Dabney of Louisa County, to Charles Dabney of Hanover County, 1 April 1795, 25; 1 p.; Negro slaves. No recordation shown.
  - Indenture. Thomas M. Dabney of Louisa County, 1 February 1796, 26; By and with the consent of his father Samuel Dabney of the said county, apprentices himself to Benjamin Tate, Tanner and Currier of the City of Richmond, for the period of three years, six months, to learn the trade of tanning and currying. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter. John Marshall, n. p., to Col. Charles Dabney, Hanover, 20 January 1800, 27; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter. James Dabney, n. p., to Col. Charles Dabney, Hanover, 3 February 1802, 28; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter. Unidentified in Fayette County, Kentucky, to Brigadier General John Guerrant in Goochland County, Virginia, 4 July 1802, 28a; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter. James Dabney, n. p., to Col. Charles Dabney, Hanover, 19 August 1802, 29; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter. Thomas Price, Woodland, to Col. [Charles Dabney?], n. p., 14 September 1803, 30; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Affidavit of Thomas Johnson, March 1804, 31; 1 p.; Of lawful age. Taken at his house in the County of Louisa which will be offered as evidence in the suit depending in the honorable the high court of chancery wherein Henry Joyce is plaintiff and Elizabeth Camron defendant. Incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. John Wickham, n. p., to Mrs. [___], Hanover, 21 March 1804, 32; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Deed. George Harris and Sarah his wife of Hanover County, to Benjamin Vaughan of the same county, 1805, 33; 1 p.; 300 acres in Hanover County. No recordation shown. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. John Guerrant, Lieutenant Governor of Virginia, in "Ceres," Goochland County, Virginia, to Major Archelaus Perkins, 20 March 1805, 33a; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Power of attorney. Charles Dabney appointed Charles Dabney, Jr., 1 January 1807, 33b; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter and declaration. Colonel Charles Dabney to unidentified recipient, July 1807, 33c; 2 pp.; Includes declaration, 24 July 1807, of Samuel Richardson attesting to Colonel Charles Dabney's military conduct. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Receipts. Payed to Charles Morris for services rendered to Colonel Charles Dabney, 1 May and 6 July 1808, 33d; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Plat. Property of [Samuel?] Dabney surveyed by David Richardson, 16 April 1813, 33e; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Charles Dabney, [Abbindon or Ablindon], Virginia, to [Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney], n. p., 20 February 1814, 34; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Charles Dabney, Salem, to [Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney], n. p., 24 February 1814, 35; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Power of attorney. Charles Dabney appointed Frances Dabney, 1817, 35a; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Power of attorney. Charles Dabney appointed John D. Andrews, 1 January 1818, 35b; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Deed. Charles Dabney of Hanover County, Virginia, to Charles Dabney, Jr. of Louisa County, Virginia, 14 December 1818, 35c; 2 pp.; A plot of land in Kentucky. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. William Wirt, Washington, to [___], 25 October 1819, 36; 4 pp.; Deals primarily with relations between the United States and Spain. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Receipts. Exchanged principally between Charles Dabney, Catharine Morris, and Charles Morris, 1818-1820, 36a; 6 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Carter Berkeley, Edge Wood, to John D. Andrews, n. p., 11 July 1825, 37; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Charles Dabney, Baltimore, to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, Jackson's Post Office, Louisa County, Virginia, 16 May 1832, 38; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Charles Dabney, Philadelphia, to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, Jackson's Post Office, Louisa County, Virginia, 18 May 1832, 39; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Charles Dabney, Philadelphia, to Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, Jackson's Post Office, Louisa County, Virginia, 27 May 1832, 40; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Charles Dabney, Washington, to [Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney], n. p., 4 June 1832, 41; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, n. p., to her son, Charles W. Dabney, Hanover, [1833], 42; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Mrs. Elizabeth Dabney, Louisa, to Charles W. Dabney, Hanover, [October 1834], 43; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. George Dabney to unidentified recipient, n. d., 43a; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Petition. Citizens of Louisa and Hanover Counties, Virginia, to the Senate and House of Representatives of the United States, n. d., 43b; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Memorandums, n. d., 43c; 2 pp.; Lists clothing delegated to officers commanding companies during the Revolutionary War. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Unidentified Dabney family member to unidentified uncle, n. d., 43d; 1 p.; Incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. Charles Dabney, Jr. to unidentified recipient, n. d., 43e; 1 p.; Incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter. George Dabney to unidentified brother, n. d., 43f; 1 p.; Incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- T. J. "Stonewall" Jackson Papers 1815-1867 (bulk, 1847-1867) (Box 1-2)
  Principally contains Civil War military correspondence, military orders, military and battle reports, military commissions, and personal correspondence to, from, and concerning General Stonewall Jackson. Personal correspondence includes extracts of letters from Stonewall Jackson to his second wife Mary Anna Morrison (1831-1915). Also in this series, there are letters written to R. L. Dabney after Jackson's death, memorandums, military records concerning Stonewall Jackson's involvement in the Mexican War, narratives of Confederate officers concerning Stonewall Jackson, newspaper clippings, and Jackson family promissory notes and receipts.
  - Promissory note. Jonathan Jackson payable to David E. Jackson, 13 February 1815, 43g; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Receipt. David E. Jackson payable to George Dahmer, 1 September 1819, 43h; 1 p.; Witnessed by Edward Jackson and Cummins Jackson. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Extracts from the reports of Generals Scott, Worth, and Pillow for the battle of Chapultepec." 1847, 44; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Return of provisions. Received and issued at Mexcoac and the City of Mexico during the month of September, 1847, 44a; 1 p.; Signed by Thomas J. Jackson
  - Letter. T. J. Jackson at Fort Hamilton, New York (State), to Minor Hall, 12 July 1849, 44b; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter. Mary J. Hays in Jane Lew, Lewis County, (West) Virginia, to an unidentified recipient, 17 March 1850, 44c; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter. [Thomas J. Jackson], Lexington, Rockbridge County, to the Board of Visitors of the University of Virginia, 2 January 1854, 45; 1 p.; Unsigned. Copy. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter. R. E. Lee, Superintendant, U. S. Military Academy, West Point, [New York], to the Board of Visitors, University of Virginia, 26 January 1854, 46; 1 p.; Recommending Thomas J. Jackson for professor of mathematics. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters. "Extracts from letters from General T. J. Jackson to his wife," [1857-1862], 47; 32 pp.; Selected and written out by Mrs. Jackson herself. Much of this matter is contained in Mrs. Jackson's memoirs of her husband. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letters. [Extracts of letters of T. J. Jackson, 1859-1862], 48; 10 pp.; Numbered 1-12 with 7 and 8 wanting. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Commission. To Thomas J. Jackson as Colonel in the Active Volunteer Forces of Virginia, 27 April 1861, 49; Signed by John Letcher. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. R. E. Lee, Head Quarters, Virginia Forces, Richmond, to Col. T. J. Jackson, commanding Virginia Volunteers at Harpers Ferry, 6 May 1861, 50; 2 pp.; Confidential. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. R. E. Lee, Head Quarters, Virginia Forces, Richmond, to Col. T. J. Jackson, Harpers Ferry, 9 May 1861, 51; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. R. E. Lee, Richmond, to Col. T. J. Jackson, Harpers Ferry, 12 May 1861, 52; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Orders No. 74. Head Quarters, C. S. Army, Harpers Ferry, 28 May 1861, 53; Re: E. K. Smith, Eugene E. McLean and W. H. C. Whiting. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Commission. To T[homas] J. Jackson as Brigadier General in the Provisional Army of the Confederate States, 17 June 1861, 54; Signed by L. P. Walker, Secretary of War. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter. W. H. C. Whiting by order of Gen. [Joseph E.] Johnston, Winchester, to Col. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 19 June 1861, 55; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter. W. H. C. Whiting, Head Quarters, Army of the Shenandoah, to Col. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 23 June 1861, 56; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter. Brig. Gen. J. E. Johnston, Winchester, to Col. [T. J.] Jackson, near Martinsburg, 2 July 1861, 57; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter. T. J. Jackson at 1st Brigade Headquarters and Camp, near Manassas, Virginia, to General G. T. Beauregard, 19 August 1861, 57a; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Orders No. 1. Head Quarters, 2nd Corps, Army of the Potomac, 25 September 1861, 58; 2 pp.; Maj. Gen. G. W. Smith announcing his staff. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Commission. To T[homas] J. Jackson as Major General in the Provisional Army of the Confederate States, 7 October 1861, 59; Signed by J. P. Benjamin, Acting Secretary of War. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Draft letter. [T. J. Jackson?], camp near Fairfax Courthouse, to J. P. Benjamin, Acting Secretary of War, 10 October 1861, 60; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter. William H. Richardson, Adjutant General's Office, to Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 14 October 1861, 61; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter. J. P. Benjamin, Acting Secretary of War, Richmond, to Maj. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, Manassas, 21 October 1861, 62; 2 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter. Blanton Duncan, Nashville, Tennessee, to [T. J. Jackson], n. p., 22 October 1861, 63; 2 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Special Orders No. 192 (Extract). Adjutant and Inspector General's Office, Richmond, Virginia, 28 October 1861, 64; 1 p.; Paragraph VII re: Major General T. J. Jackson. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Commission. To T[homas] J. Jackson as Major, Corps Artillery, in the Army of the Confederate States, 31 October 1861, 65; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter. R. H. Chilton, Assistant Adjutant General, Adjutant General's Office, Richmond, to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Winchester, 19 November 1861, 66; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter. A. T. Bledsoe, Chief, Bureau of War, War Department, C. S. A., Richmond, to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Winchester, 23 November 1861, 67; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter. Gen. J. E. Johnston, Centreville, to Maj. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, n. p., 23 November 1861, 68; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter. T. J. Jackson at Headquarters for the Valley District, Winchester, Virginia, to Colonel E. Sipe, 26 November 1861, 68a; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter. J. P. Benjamin, Secretary of War, Richmond, to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Winchester, 6 December 1861, 69; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. "Rebel Friend", Yankeedom, to "My Good Old Friend", n. p., 20 December 1861, 70; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, Winchester, to Maj. T. G. Rhett, n. p., 21 December 1861, 71; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, to Gen. S[amuel] Cooper, Richmond, 23 December 1861, 72; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. A. S. Pendleton, A. D. C., Head Quarters, Valley District, to Brig. Gen. R. B. Garnett, n. p., 24 December 1861, 73; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, Winchester, to Maj. T. G. Rhett, n. p., 24 December 1861, 74; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. General J. E. Johnston, Centreville, to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Winchester, 25 December 1861, 75; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, to Gen. S[amuel] Cooper, Richmond, 26 December 1861, 76; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. G. G. Junkin, Head Quarters, Valley District, to Lt. Col. Turner Ashby, n. p., 27 December 1861, 77; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. [Gov.] John Letcher, Richmond, to Maj. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, n. p., 28 December 1861, 78; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Circular. By command of Maj. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, 31 December 1861, 79; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, Ungers Store, to Gen. J. E. Johnston, Commanding Department of Northern Virginia, n. p., 10 January 1862, 80; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, Romney, to Maj. Thomas G. Rhett, A. A. G., Department of Northern Virginia, n. p., 16 January 1862, 81; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, Romney, to J. P. Benjamin, Secretary of War, [Richmond], 20 January 1862, 82; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Charges and specifications preferred by Major Gen. T. J. Jackson, P. A. C. S. against Brig. Gen. W. W. Loring, P. A. C. S., 26 January 1862, 83; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, to J. P. Benjamin, Secretary of War, 31 January 1862, 84; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter. [Gen. J. E. Johnston?], Centreville, to Maj. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, n. p., 3 February 1862, 85; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, Winchester, to Maj. Thomas G. Rhett, n. p., 1 February 1862, 86; 1 p.; Also contains note. Jackson to Rhett, 4 February 1862. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter. [Gov. John Letcher], Richmond, to [Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson], n. p., 4 February 1862, 87; 1 p.; Incomplete. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General Orders No. 21, Head Quarters, Department Northern Virginia, 4 February 1862, 88; 2 pp.; Issued by Gen. [J. E.] Johnston. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter. The Rev. Francis McFarland, Mint Spring, Augusta County, to Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, n. p., 5 February 1862, 89; 4 pp. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter. John T. Harris, Harrisonburg, to Maj. Gen. Thomas J. Jackson, Winchester, 6 February 1862, 90; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter. J. M. Bennett, Richmond, to [Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson], n. p., 7 February 1862, 91; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Draft battle report. [Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson], Winchester, to [Gen. J. E. Johnston], 7 February 1862, 92; 15 pp.; Re: the winter campaign in the Shenandoah Valley, 1861-1862. Written by a clerk with corrections and additions by Gen. Jackson and Mrs. Jackson. Also contains copy incorporating the additions and corrections. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter. G. G. Junkin, A. D. C., Head Quarters, Valley District, to Col. Sincendiver, n. p., 11 February 1862, 93; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter. Maj. Gen. T. J. Jackson, Head Quarters, Valley District, Winchester, to Gen. Joseph E. Johnston, n. p., 24 February 1862, 94; 3 pp. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter. G. G. Junkin, A. D. C., Head Quarters, Valley District, to Capt. George W. Myers, n. p., 24 February 1862, 95; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter. T. J. Jackson at Winchester, Virginia, to an unidentified recipient, 6 March 1862, 95a; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter. [Gen. Joseph E. Johnston], n. p., to Maj. Gen. [T. J.] Jackson, n. p., 18 March 1862, 96; 1 p. (Box 1, Folder 11)